<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Javascript on Machiaweliczny s0ftwar3 d3v3l0pm3nt discoveries ;)</title>
    <link>http://machiaweliczny.github.io/categories/javascript/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Javascript on Machiaweliczny s0ftwar3 d3v3l0pm3nt discoveries ;)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:26:25 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://machiaweliczny.github.io/categories/javascript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Jscodeshift</title>
      <link>http://machiaweliczny.github.io/post/jscodeshift/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:26:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://machiaweliczny.github.io/post/jscodeshift/</guid>
      <description>If you need to do some bigger refactoring then I can recommend using Jscodeshift which allows you to do AST-to-AST code conversion and pretty prints it. You can read more about it here - https://medium.com/@cpojer/effective-javascript-codemods-5a6686bb46fb
For prototing there&amp;rsquo;s great website called https://astexplorer.net/ where you can test prototype modifications. Remember to use ctrl+space after typing . for avaiable API hints when using first time.
You can see how to write scripts here - https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyperapp</title>
      <link>http://machiaweliczny.github.io/post/hyperapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 10:14:29 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://machiaweliczny.github.io/post/hyperapp/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s quite popular JS lib that&amp;rsquo;s 315 lines of code and has capabilities of react + redux in it. It&amp;rsquo;s called Hyperapp and you can view the code there https://github.com/hyperapp/hyperapp/blob/master/src/index.js. I need to investigate how actions part is done and maybe it&amp;rsquo;s viable solution if you care about minimal size and want something sane.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modern Frontend Explained</title>
      <link>http://machiaweliczny.github.io/post/modern-frontend-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 08:37:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://machiaweliczny.github.io/post/modern-frontend-explained/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s cool series of articles at medium from Peter Jang explaining evolution of frontend approaches to JS, CSS and structuring applicaitons. I highly recommend it for anyone starting with frontend.
 modern CSS explained modern JS explained comparing frontend approaches  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State of JS 2017</title>
      <link>http://machiaweliczny.github.io/post/stateofjs2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 15:32:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://machiaweliczny.github.io/post/stateofjs2017/</guid>
      <description>If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read yet it&amp;rsquo;s good to get through some JS ecosystem surveys like stateofjs or risingstars
The tech I presonally started using recently(after switching to frontend only role) is:
 VS Code - I was using atom before but it felt a little slugish, so after switching to Typescript I started using VS Code and I&amp;rsquo;m happier. Atom keybindings extension made transition painless. Would like to have code outline natively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VS Code Run Script on Selected Text</title>
      <link>http://machiaweliczny.github.io/post/vs-code-run-script-on-selected-text/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 13:11:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://machiaweliczny.github.io/post/vs-code-run-script-on-selected-text/</guid>
      <description>I was looking for ability to run some scripts on selected text on vs-code and couln&amp;rsquo;t find native support for it.
But I&amp;rsquo;ve found not so well know extension which does exactly that - https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=yhirose.FilterText When your script is available in shell you can easily run it on selected text in editor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VS Code</title>
      <link>http://machiaweliczny.github.io/post/vscode/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 11:00:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://machiaweliczny.github.io/post/vscode/</guid>
      <description>I just want to mention that recently I&amp;rsquo;ve switched fully to VS Code for Typescript development and it&amp;rsquo;s simply great. So if you haven&amp;rsquo;t tried it yet - I can totaly recommend it.
Just remember to click at everthing in &amp;ldquo;Learn&amp;rdquo; in Welcome page as this is great introduction to interface.
There are keymaps(bindings) for other popular editors, so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to learn new keybinding or configure them by yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stackblitz</title>
      <link>http://machiaweliczny.github.io/post/stackblitz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 10:56:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://machiaweliczny.github.io/post/stackblitz/</guid>
      <description>I have stumbled upon https://stackblitz.com/ ala JS fiddle online code editor which utilises VS Code and let&amp;rsquo;s you easily share the results. Looks cool and they have designed some new package manager for it - https://medium.com/@ericsimons/introducing-turbo-5x-faster-than-yarn-npm-and-runs-natively-in-browser-cc2c39715403</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating Angularjs to Webpack</title>
      <link>http://machiaweliczny.github.io/post/migrating-angularjs-to-webpack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 10:39:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://machiaweliczny.github.io/post/migrating-angularjs-to-webpack/</guid>
      <description>Recently I had to work on Angularjs(1.X) codebase and I dedided that it needed and update of build process to match modern standards and gain great tooling support that comes with it.
It was using grunt and with the help of these two articles I successfuly migrated to webpack:
 https://medium.com/appifycanada/migrate-to-webpack-from-grunt-bower-legacy-build-system-344526f47873 https://medium.com/eventmobi/how-to-incrementally-switch-to-webpack-203a1b431f7a  As grunt requires files in alphabetical order you have to imitate this with webpack and the most important part of code is this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ParcelJs</title>
      <link>http://machiaweliczny.github.io/post/parceljs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 10:18:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://machiaweliczny.github.io/post/parceljs/</guid>
      <description>Recently I tested parceljs - bundler advertised as zero config and it delivered.
Actually I had to do one thing to make it work with typescript: npm i typescript
You simply run it like this parcel index.html and use &amp;lt;script scr=&amp;quot;index.ts&amp;quot; /&amp;gt; inside.
Quite good alternative to webpack for greenfield projects but for more complex/legacy projects I would stay with webpack.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>